Fric Constantinides

eric@ericconstantinides.com San Jose, CA | (415) 571-6764





Intro

In a nutshell: I'm am a Front-end UI Engineer specializing in React, Redux, CSS, and Vanilla JS.

Most Recently: I'm a React / UI Engineer at Insureon working on the Customer Portal Web App using React and JavaScript.

Previously: I was working on BottomlessBrunch.com, a React and Redux based web app. Before that I was Lead Front-End Developer at EverSport Media. Before that I was a Web Developer at Flickerbox in San Francisco.

Experience

Insureon in San Jose, CA

January, 2018 - Current

Front-end UI Engineer: Co-engineer for building a new customer portal site for Insureon. Portal is built using React, Webpack, CSS Modules, Post-CSS, Babel, React Router, etc. Created custom JavaScript field and validation framework for fast Object-based prototyping of forms and its validation.

• Customer Portal (2018) Javascript / React Engineer, React, Webpack, CSS Modules, Post CSS, JavaScript

BottomlessBrunch.com in San Jose, CA

April, 2017 - January, 2018

Full-Stack UI Engineer: Developed bottomlessbrunch.com, a React and Redux responsive web-app which graphically renders "bottomless" brunch locations in the United States. Integrated Google Maps, Google Places, and YELP APIs. Created administration back-end which combines multiple APIs to create new locations in seconds. Served on an AWS Server through an NGINX proxy with a Node/Express API.

EverSport Media Online Video Provider in Los Gatos, CA

Sep, 2015 - Jan, 2017

Lead Front-end Developer: Lead Front-end Developer for Eversport's themes and modules using JavaScript, SCSS / CSS, Drupal and PHP. Designed and developed the site and the user-interface for the Single Page App media player that ran on 3rd party sites.

EverSport.tv (2015-2017) Lead Front-End Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass PHP

• Single Page App (2015-2017) Lead Front-End Developer, Co-Designer, JavaScript, JSON, AJAX, Sass

Flickerbox, Inc. Agency in San Francisco, CA

Jan, 2012 - June, 2015

Senior Web Developer (Jan, 2014 - June, 2015): Orchestrated the weekly developer meetings; drafted timelines and estimates for future projects; composed technical briefs for client-side contracts; lead web development projects.

Web Developer (Jan, 2012 - Jan, 2014): Architected content structure for websites. Hand-coded HTML, SCSS (CSS), and JS from designs into responsive and interactive pages. Implemented JavaScript libraries and wrote custom JavaScript/jQuery code.

- PureStorage.com (2015) Lead Developer, JavaScript, Sass, WordPress
- Adallom.com (2015) Lead Developer, WordPress CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Platfora.com (2014) Lead Developer, WordPress CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Alteryx.com (2014) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Okta.com (2014) Lead Developer, PHP, JavaScript, Sass, WordPress

- Abaxis.com/veterinary (2013) Lead Developer, JavaScript, Sass, WordPress
- SocialChorus.com (2013) Lead Developer, WordPress CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Pentaho.com (2013) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- LiveOps.com (2012) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, CSS
- IslandResortAndCasino.com (2012) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, CSS

Full MERN Stack Web-App Developer. Previously, Full LAMP Stack Developer:

- MineSweeper (2017)
 - Developer / Designer, React, Redux, JavaScript, Sass
- MuddlingThroughCode.com (2017)
 - Developer / Designer, Node, Express, JavaScript, Sass
- EricConstantinides.com (2017)
 - Developer / Designer, React, JSON, Sass
- ConstantlyBeing.com (2017)
 - Lead Developer, Designer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Annachich.com (2016)
 - Lead Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal, Drupal Commerce, JavaScript, Sass
- PaoloShoes.com (2015)
 - Lead Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal CMS, UberCart, JavaScript, Sass

- CameronVailDesign.com (2016)
 Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- DukeDuchess.com (2011)

Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, Ubercart, JavaScript, CSS

• Bike To Work Day: YouCanBikeThere.com

(2008, 2009, 2010, 2011)

Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, CSS

• BottomlessBrunch.com (2011)

Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, CSS

• ChicFashionWeekSF.com (2010)

Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, CSS

• BayAreaBikes.org (2008)

Lead Developer | Lead Designer, Drupal CMS, CSS

Skills

Primary Skills My main area of concentration

- React, JSX, Redux, Create-React-App
- JavaScript, AJAX, JSON, ES2015 / ES6, ES2016, lodash
- Testing, Jest, Enzyme
- Node, Express, mongoDB, npm / yarn
- JS Tools, Gulp, Webpack, Babel

- CSS, Sass/SCSS, BEM CSS, FlexBox
- HTML, HTML5
- Git, GitHub, BitBucket, SourceTree
- User Experience (UX), User Interface (UI), Responsive Web Design (RWD)

Supplementary Skills Important proficiencies that aren't my primary focus

- Design Apps, PhotoShop, Illustrator
- Front-end helpers, jQuery, Bootstrap
- PHP, SQL, MySQL
- CMS Theming, Drupal (advanced), WordPress
- Online Tools, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Jira
- Marketing Automation, Eloqua, Salesforce, Marketo
- Cloud Hosting, Acquia, Amazon Web Services, DigitalOcean VPS
- Code Editing, Sublime Text, Visual Studio Code, Chrome Developer Tools
- Apache, Unix, HTTPS/SSL

Education

W.P. Carey School of Business in Tempe, AZ

Arizona State University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems (CIS): 3.75 Computer Information Systems GPA **Bachelor of Science, Marketing:** 4.0 Marketing GPA